<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on AIT DSAI</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Home on AIT DSAI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ait-dsai.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Projects | Cultural Data Science</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/projects/cultural-data-science/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/projects/cultural-data-science/</guid><description>Cultural Data Science Advancing digital methods for the management and analysis of cultural heritage Data is becoming an increasingly important resource in Cultural Heritage. AIT Cultural Data Science provides services and solutions to support digitalization in national libraries, archives, galleries, museums, as well as in academic humanities research. Our research field has its roots in the turn of the century, at which time cultural institutions in Europe were beginning to digitize their holdings and make them available to citizens in digital form.</description></item><item><title>Projects | Industrial Data Science</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/projects/industrial-data-science/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/projects/industrial-data-science/</guid><description>Industrial Data Science DSAI investigates and applies data analytics approaches to gain new insights in to industrial processes The digital transformation provides industries with unparalleled opportunities for value creation. In this new context, data has become one of the main sources for innovation and business success. When properly tamed, the massive amounts of data companies have today can lead to enhanced business operation, costs reduction, and powerful decision-making strategies. DSAI’s Industrial Data Science (IDS) portfolio can help firms make the most of their data, to conquer the digital transformation challenges.</description></item><item><title>Projects | Public Security</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/projects/public-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/projects/public-security/</guid><description>Public Security DSAI makes the internet safer for European citizens The Internet is an unprecedented platform for communication, information and commerce. At the same time, it is an unprecedented platform for disinformation, fraud and criminal activity. The rapid pace of technological change makes regulation and enforcement in this digital realm difficult. DSAI cooperates with public authorities and law enforcement to make the internet safer for citizens and commerce, in three crucial areas: Digital Forensics, Virtual Asset analysis, and Consumer Protection.</description></item></channel></rss>