<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on AIT DSAI</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on AIT DSAI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ait-dsai.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/about/</guid><description>About About DSAI AIT’s Data Science &amp;amp; Artificial Intelligence (DSAI) unit offers Data Science research services for scalable Artificial Intelligence (AI) applications. The team provides data science consulting and solutions for making informed decisions based on large, heterogeneous, and real-time data under strict conditions of IT security and data protection. DSAI is a multidisciplinary group of experienced scientists and engineers with diverse backgrounds - from data analytics, applied mathematics and statistics, to information security, and the humanities.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Contact</description></item><item><title>Projects | Cultural Data Science</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/projects/cultural-data-science/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/projects/cultural-data-science/</guid><description>Cultural Data Science Advancing digital methods for the management and analysis of cultural heritage Data is becoming an increasingly important resource in Cultural Heritage. AIT Cultural Data Science provides services and solutions to support digitalization in national libraries, archives, galleries, museums, as well as in academic humanities research. Our research field has its roots in the turn of the century, at which time cultural institutions in Europe were beginning to digitize their holdings and make them available to citizens in digital form.</description></item><item><title>Projects | Industrial Data Science</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/projects/industrial-data-science/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/projects/industrial-data-science/</guid><description>Industrial Data Science DSAI investigates and applies data analytics approaches to gain new insights in to industrial processes The digital transformation provides industries with unparalleled opportunities for value creation. In this new context, data has become one of the main sources for innovation and business success. When properly tamed, the massive amounts of data companies have today can lead to enhanced business operation, costs reduction, and powerful decision-making strategies. DSAI’s Industrial Data Science (IDS) portfolio can help firms make the most of their data, to conquer the digital transformation challenges.</description></item><item><title>Projects | Public Security</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/projects/public-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/projects/public-security/</guid><description>Public Security</description></item><item><title>Research | Applied AI</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/ai-audio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/ai-audio/</guid><description>Artificial Intelligence Audio Audio perception is one of the central research fields in artificial intelligence. This complex and diverse cognitive task is particularly relevant in security applications for the perception and interpretation of scenes, events and potential threats. At AIT, we focus on applied tasks such as acoustic scene interpretation and understanding, audio event detection in public and domestic environments as well as in media, anomalous sound detection, detection of audio manipulations, bioacoustics in medical applications, and the complex cognitive task of modelling subjective human perceptions such as emotions in speech and music.</description></item><item><title>Research | Applied AI</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/applied-ai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/applied-ai/</guid><description>Applied Artificial Intelligence Artificial Intelligence (AI) is a complex and diverse research field, ranging from technical to ethical and legal aspects. Applying AI solutions responsibly in a socio-technological environment requires comprehensive understanding and control of all components and technologies. At AIT we focus on partial aspects of AI, such as AI-Audio, network analysis, explainable AI, but also on the big picture. Artificial intelligence does not consist of a simple machine learning based computer vision model but is the realization of a complex cognitive task consisting of several components from different research disciplines.</description></item><item><title>Research | Explainable AI</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/explainable-ai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/explainable-ai/</guid><description>Explainable AI</description></item><item><title>Research | Multimodal AI</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/multimodal-ai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/multimodal-ai/</guid><description>Multi-modal Artificial Intelligence The definition of intelligence is diverse, and so is the definition of artificial intelligence. Yet most mainstream Artificial Intelligence (AI) solutions simplify a task to a Machine Learning problem using a single sensory modality such as images or videos. By this, relevant information such as the audio layer of videos or the text of document images is neglected. Here at AIT, we focus on the complex task of harnessing and combining information from multiple modalities to develop higher-level cognitive AI systems.</description></item><item><title>Research | NLP</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/nlp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/nlp/</guid><description>Natural Language Processing Language understanding is a cognitive task at the highest level and a major discipline of artificial intelligence. Natural Language Processing (NLP) enables us to interpret written as well as spoken language and to extract and learn contextual information relevant for our application domains. AIT provides the expertise and support for a broad range of use cases with regard to large text corpora. We apply a variety of machine-learning techniques – including algorithmics, mathematics and statistics as well as deep-learning techniques – to discover topics and semantic relationships, and to extract meaningful, structured information.</description></item><item><title>Team</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/team/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/team/</guid><description>Team</description></item></channel></rss>