<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research on AIT DSAI</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on AIT DSAI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Research | AI Audio</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/ai-audio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/ai-audio/</guid><description>Artificial Intelligence Audio Audio perception is one of the central research fields in artificial intelligence. This complex and diverse cognitive task is particularly relevant in security applications for the perception and interpretation of scenes, events and potential threats. At AIT, we focus on applied tasks such as acoustic scene interpretation and understanding, audio event detection in public and domestic environments as well as in media, anomalous sound detection, detection of audio manipulations, bioacoustics in medical applications, and the complex cognitive task of modelling subjective human perceptions such as emotions in speech and music.</description></item><item><title>Research | Applied AI</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/applied-ai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/applied-ai/</guid><description>Applied Artificial Intelligence Artificial Intelligence (AI) is a complex and diverse research field, ranging from technical to ethical and legal aspects. Applying AI solutions responsibly in a socio-technological environment requires comprehensive understanding and control of all components and technologies. At AIT we focus on partial aspects of AI, such as AI-Audio, network analysis, explainable AI, but also on the big picture. Artificial intelligence does not consist of a simple machine learning based computer vision model but is the realization of a complex cognitive task consisting of several components from different research disciplines.</description></item><item><title>Research | Explainable AI</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/explainable-ai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/explainable-ai/</guid><description>Explainable AI</description></item><item><title>Research | Multimodal AI</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/multimodal-ai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/multimodal-ai/</guid><description>Multi-modal Artificial Intelligence The definition of intelligence is diverse, and so is the definition of artificial intelligence. Yet most mainstream Artificial Intelligence (AI) solutions simplify a task to a Machine Learning problem using a single sensory modality such as images or videos. By this, relevant information such as the audio layer of videos or the text of document images is neglected. Here at AIT, we focus on the complex task of harnessing and combining information from multiple modalities to develop higher-level cognitive AI systems.</description></item><item><title>Research | NLP</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/nlp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:10:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/research/nlp/</guid><description>Natural Language Processing Language understanding is a cognitive task at the highest level and a major discipline of artificial intelligence. Natural Language Processing (NLP) enables us to interpret written as well as spoken language and to extract and learn contextual information relevant for our application domains. AIT provides the expertise and support for a broad range of use cases with regard to large text corpora. We apply a variety of machine-learning techniques – including algorithmics, mathematics and statistics as well as deep-learning techniques – to discover topics and semantic relationships, and to extract meaningful, structured information.</description></item></channel></rss>