<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Topics on AIT DSAI</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/topics/</link><description>Recent content in Topics on AIT DSAI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 10:47:02 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ait-dsai.github.io/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fake News</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/topics/fake-news/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 10:56:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/topics/fake-news/</guid><description>Fake News Text
Contact</description></item><item><title>Predictive Analytics</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/topics/predictive-analytics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 10:55:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/topics/predictive-analytics/</guid><description>Predictive Analytics At AIT we use historical data, statistical algorithms and machine learning techniques to predict future events. The historical data is used to build a mathematical model that captures important trends. The goal is to go beyond knowing what happened in the past, to providing a best assessment of what will happen in the future. We can then suggest actions to take for optimal outcomes. Predictive analytics is therefore a powerful tool for detecting fraud, predicting customer behavior, improving operations and reducing risk.</description></item><item><title>Predictive Maintenance</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/topics/predictive-maintenance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 10:54:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/topics/predictive-maintenance/</guid><description>Predictive Maintenance Predictive maintenance refers to a holistic approach to monitoring the history and condition of industrial equipment in order to determine when maintenance activities should be carried out. AIT trains and applies machine-learning models to detect degradations of machines or machine parts, allowing them to predict future equipment failures. This provides an informed basis for proactive decisions by maintenance planning and can thus reduce the costs related to unexpected machine breakdowns.</description></item><item><title>Home</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/topics/network-analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 10:52:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/topics/network-analysis/</guid><description>Network Analysis Network Security and Anomaly Detection AI can largely increase the detection accuracy of attacks and other threats flowing through the network and impacting end devices, without sacrificing the robustness of the analysis (i.e., false alarms). AI can also improve the automatic detection and diagnosis of the ever-growing number of anomalies occurring in all sort of complex systems, including data networks but not limited to that. By enabling the analysis of highly-dimensional data with both real-time and large-scale requirements, AI and big data principles and platforms can significantly improve the visibility and understanding of cybersecurity events and anomalies, empowering an efficient diagnosis process.</description></item><item><title>Consumer Protection</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/topics/consumer-protection/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 10:47:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/topics/consumer-protection/</guid><description>Consumer Protection Prevention is a key instrument in fighting cybercrime. Technological solutions that actively inform, enlighten and protect consumers and their representative bodies are an important addition to preventive measures both in terms of capacity and speed in fighting illegitimate subscription services, counterfeit goods and fraudulent e-commerce offerings. AIT provides an integrated pipeline for stakeholders reaching from data acquisition to Machine Learning (ML) based methods and Open Source tools and services that are applied at scale such as the fake-shop detector that are both, closely integrated in the day to day use cases of stakeholders (e.</description></item><item><title>Public Safety</title><link>http://ait-dsai.github.io/topics/public-safety/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 10:47:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ait-dsai.github.io/topics/public-safety/</guid><description>Public Safety AIT provides solutions for the forensic analysis of audio-video material, with features that address the requirements of end users including service providers and stakeholders such as law enforcement agencies (LEAs). Our solution supports LEAs in analysing, processing, and gaining information from large amounts of evidence data, such as video or audio recordings, pictures, and internet web pages. It deals with heterogeneity, varying quality of data acquired from a wide variety of data sources, and allows investigators to identify vehicles, weapons, sounds, sentences, and key words, and link them to relevant events.</description></item></channel></rss>